I'm will Shi gas and connect with Mr bav
Das Gupta managing director and CEO with
ICC Lombard uh Mr Gupta good morning
thank you for joining us now you've
reported a pad growth of 35% for the
quarter gone by tell us what transpired
for you in this quarter and where did
the growth largely come
from so yeah we had a very good um you
know quarter uh this quarter end um with
a roughly about 20% PBT growth and a 35%
pad growth uh driven by uh most aspects
of business so if you look at our
underwriting numbers our combined ratio
was sub 100 so that was one uh positive
uh the investment book also uh performed
well uh so all in all and you know we
obviously did a lot of work in terms of
uh containing cost and uh you know
focusing on quality of underwriting uh
and all of that helped out in terms of
the uh profit growth that we've seen for
this quarter one more thing that you um
must keep in mind is that when I
explained the pbd growth number versus
the pad growth number this was probably
the last quarter where we we have the
differential tax rate uh last year at
this point in time we had a higher tax
rate now with the tax rates having come
down to 25% we have had that benefit
relative to PBT growth uh in terms of
pad
growth now the pandemic in a sense has
also had impact on the way how health
insurance and motor insurance two
categories have moved obviously Car
Sales were less so this would have
impacted your uh Health insur if your
motor insurance business so could you
give us a sense of the health vertical
and and the motor insurance business
vertical uh look for us uh you know
traditionally uh motor has been a larger
share of our business uh but
incrementally Health has been uh
catching up and now if you look at the
health segment there are three or four
components one is the corporate Health
business uh which is um uh basically
what you provide to uh you know
employers for their employees that
segment has continued do well largely
driven by the uh you know need for
health insurance for employees the
second is the retail segment where
individuals buy policies on on their own
now there there are two types of
policies that we sell one is benefit
policy which is basically a fixed amount
of compensation that we uh provide for
specified illnesses U that segment is
largely driven by Bank assurance and uh
you know attachment sales through nbfcs
that segment hasn't done well uh but the
other segment in retail which is retail
Indemnity which is largely uh you know
hospitalization uh cover uh largely sold
through you know agents that segment has
done really well uh for us uh and if you
see uh that segment that's grown roughly
about 37% for uh the Q2 and within that
if you look at new uh you know new uh
customers coming in versus renewals the
new numbers have grown under about 48%
in this quarter
okay you also mentioned that Health has
grown by more than 40% is that
sustainable according to you or do you
believe we at an inflection point at
this you know at this juncture and that
uh you know we'll only see growth
continue so if a question is is this an
inflection point the answer is yes it is
an inflection point in terms of
awareness of the necessity to have
protection for health uh and and to that
extent I think there's a change in uh
mind share that we have as a product
category in in consumer mind whether the
growth numbers will sustain I would
doubt because there will be some amount
of Base effect that will play through
next year uh as we go through this year
because the base of last year uh Visa
the increase demand that we are seeing
probably will continue even if it gets
slightly moderated in the second half
the growth numbers should remain
reasonably high but on that base next
year we will uh definitely not have the
same kind of growth numbers in our
expectation but is it an inflection
point in terms of overall health
insurance as a category definitely it is
it
is sure okay talk about the recent
acquisition as well of bti AA
predominantly a motor player given that
we have seen an uptick in that segment
you actually see numbers getting even
better
there so the motor insurance segment has
probably been the most uh badly affected
in the first 6 months but we are seeing
uh positive pickup uh in the festive
season uh you've seen the CM numbers
that was more in terms of uh restocking
industry but on the ground also we are
seeing a good Traction in the
dealerships so we are hopeful that the
festive season will do well uh for the
US uh we will have to wait to see how it
pans out in the quarter 4 of this year
uh and if it continues to sustain then
you know that should be a big positive
on balance uh the negative impact that
we saw on on motor in the first half is
probably overplayed and we will now see
Improvement in the in the motor segment
as well coming to your question on BH AA
yes they are also relatively strong in
uh motor but even if you look at
collectively we will be about 12% market
share in motor so we still have a long
way to
go right your company would also focus
on bringing the combined entity back to
operating levels of about 100% as we
understand in terms of the combined
ratio share with us what's the strategy
and what is it that are the timelines
that you've set for
yourself so our combined is uh as we
speak already uh less than 100 and this
is in spite of uh uh some oneoff hits
that we've had particularly uh due to
flood losses uh and we also beginning to
see some elevated covid uh claims in the
coming through in the health side uh so
the focus of the company has always been
to uh you know deliver uh quality
underwriting numbers and by underwriting
numbers if you keep your combined ratio
uh 100 or sub 100 ideally that means you
are creating uh you know value in terms
of underwriting uh so that's something
that we will continue to do and the
strategy largely has been three or four
uh you know aspects one is um a a
complete focus on risk selection driven
by a lot of analytics that we've been
able to uh you know build analytic you
engines that we've been able to buil
over the years uh we have an advantage
of being in the industry for 20 years
we've looked at data over these years
and we've built models to do better risk
selection so risk selection using data
and analytics is uh key second is uh a
lot of focus on digitization and uh
technology adoption to keep costs under
control as also provide convenience to
our customers and third and this is I
think very important is a focus on claim
service because at the end of the day we
really want to do uh you know serve our
better customers well and uh and that's
where we believe a brand and institution
gets built so claim service is the third
element it may not obviously you know
you may not think it's obvious when it
comes to underwriting but in the long
term it does play a big
role sure digitization clearly has
managed to help and Aid the entire
Insurance sector how's been the response
to the various age cohorts a and has
there been any increase that you've seen
in Millennial participation in demand
coming in from tier 2 and three
cities so the way we look at
digitization is not just in terms of uh
reaching out to customers that of course
is an important element of our
digitization strategy how do we reach
out to Millennials how do we reach out
to uh you know customers through digital
channels uh but digitization for us is U
all encompassing it is including you
know not just in terms of policy
sourcing but also in terms of servicing
in terms of claims in terms of internal
processes so we look at all of that uh
you know uh keeping a lens of digital in
mind and I'll give you a couple of uh
you know examples so um let's look at
claims so one of the things that we
launched couple of years back was a uh
you know app based uh video survey for
uh you know for motor claims uh and
that's something that we uh launched to
one to streamline process and make it
more effective cost effective for us but
even more importantly for making more
convenient for customers now the
percentage of motor claims that we're
getting processed through our uh this
instas spect app uh was in the high 20s
was the you know latter half of last
year in Q4 of last year that number uh
on a run rate basis in the month of
September has crossed 60% that tells you
about the adoption of
digitization uh coming back to your
specific question on what's happening in
the smaller towns and you know rural
India one of the initiatives again we
had uh adopted about couple of years
back was uh virtual offices uh basically
offices which are uh we don't have a
physical Branch but we have a team which
is running the business completely uh
you know virtually using a tech stack uh
that segment the Virtual Office segment
is largely catering to the smaller towns
um where the the business model is not
scaled up to justify setting up a
physical Branch now that segment in this
quarter has grown at about 49% so I
think if you look at across board on the
digitization side there's been a lot of
uh Focus that we've put in and and we've
seen reaping benefits last one that I'll
talk about in terms of consumer is um uh
for health for example we launched our I
take care app which basically provides a
lot of wellness and support services for
health customers and we've added other
elements now uh we've had more than 2
lakh downloads of that app in this
period and through that app excuse me
we've been been providing uh for example
homebased care we've been providing
telec Consulting all of that is becoming
very popular
today and finally uh Mr Das
Gupta given that interest rates are low
and there is a drop in bond yields how
exactly do you see your treasury
business moving because that in a sense
has been a very large main state for
your
profits look we don't give a guidance on
exact profit growth uh but if you look
at our investment portfolio um we've had
uh you know two good quarters um when
you look at the benign um interest
environment obviously the uh Bond
portfolio and you know roughly about 80
85% of our book is held in uh you know
GX and uh high quality corporate bonds
uh obviously the mark to Market of that
Bond portfolio is very positive at this
point in time that doesn't mean that we
would want to take those profits out we
would want to take a call on interest
rates based on our view of interest
rates now not to kind of do profit
management um but just specifically to
answer your uh you know question on how
the portfolio has done um you know this
half the realized return on the
portfolio was about
7.8% we believe that uh given the uh
overall mix of portfolio the quality of
uh Investments that we have uh and the
directional view of interest rates our
view is that our Investment Portfolio
should continue to deliver somewhere
around 7 7 and a half% return on
investment going forward
all right thanks for joining us then
this morning and uh taking us through
the latest trends we're going to take a
very quick break on that note back in
just a moment